He can think whatever he wants.
He calls the media the enemies of the people.
You call him a fascist?
Yeah.
You can say whatever you want.
Yes.
But the president is, I'm not the president
of the United States with executive power
to crack down on the media.
So then the First Amendment only applies to the citizens,
but not the president of the United States?
I never said that.
OK, so then he can say.
In fact, Donald Trump runs his mouth more than anyone.
Absolutely, he does.
He is.
And he doesn't just say stuff, as I say.
He actually does stuff.
He actually does crack down.
For example, Fifth Amendment.
Yes.
Due process.
Judges have actually said, you have violated due process.
Yes, except for people kind of forget
Clinton, the 1996 Immigration Reform Act,
where you can get limited due process when
you have expedited.
American citizens?
No.
What about American citizens?
Who's getting deported that's American?
Two American children have been deported multiple this year.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Their parents have been deported, and their parents
say, I'm going to take my baby.
No, the father was American.
No.
Was mom legal?
We don't know, because they didn't go to court.
And the judge, by the way.
They don't have to go to court.
Yes.
That's not a part of the due process.
Are you a lawyer?
I'm very aware of that.
Do I have to be?
Oh, oh, we're making an argument now from we're making it.
It's a simple question.
Are you a lawyer?
OK.
We're making an argument.
I'll take that as a no.
A Trump-appointed judge in the case,
not some Marxist lefty judges you people like to call them.
A Trump-appointed conservative judge
said you cannot, it is illegal and unconstitutional,
to expel or deport an American citizen
without meaningful process.
He said that in April.
So that was an act that Trump did.
It wasn't speech.
He got rid of an American citizen
from the country without process.
That's the Fifth Amendment violation.
Since I'm not up to date on that specific case.
I'll give you more.
I'm sure you can.
So.
Well, you weren't aware that American citizens
were being deported.
It's a pretty big story.
Yeah, the child that probably wouldn't come up.
Maybe if you read the fake news, you might know.
What?
If you read the fake news, you might know what's going on.
A lot of American citizens have been deported.
Oh, how would I know what's going on if I read fake news?
I don't watch CNN or Rachel Maddow.
Sorry.
That's why you don't know that your fellow citizens have
been deported this year.
My fellow citizens, no.
Are they not American citizens that haven't been deported?
OK.
When a child goes with their adult.
All right, guys.
That's time.
Please return to your seat.
Nice to meet you.
Hey.
Before we go any further, we want
to take a moment to say thanks so much to Straight Error
News for powering the Fact Chats in this video.
Straight Error News is on a mission
to raise the bar on journalism in a time of media bias
and mistrust.
Straight Error News helps you quickly
find trusted information you need to understand the news,
allowing you to dive deep into the topics that matter to you
and the world around you.
Their work is trying to break the bias bubble,
helping you understand how every side of the political spectrum
is reporting on a story so you get
a full picture of the news.
That's why we're so happy to be partnering
with Straight Error News.
They deliver the facts, unbiased, balanced,
and designed to make sense of a complex world,
getting you the clarity you deserve
and news you can trust.
Go to san.com slash surrounded or click
the link in the description to check it out.
By clicking that link, you're not just
supporting this channel.
You also take advantage of a better way
to get the news.
Welcome back to Trustworthy Journalism.
Thanks again to Straight Error News for partnering with us
on this episode.
Now, let's get into it.
My next claim is that immigrants overall are good for America.
Oh, no, Daniella, you beat me.
Hi, how are you?
Hello, nice to meet you.
Daniella.
So in regards to your claim, I just
want to start by asking this.
Do you care more about helping Americans or immigrants
in this claim?
Immigrants are Americans.
I'm an immigrant.
I'm an American.
Well, immigrants are not Americans.
Americans are the people that were born here.
That's not true.
What's the basis of your claim for that?
Are you talking about people that
get naturalized in the process of becoming American?
Yes, 14th Amendment.
Have you read it?
OK, yes, I have.
Citizenship clause.
It says, any persons born or naturalized in the United
States are citizens of the United States.
I'm aware of that.
There's about 40 to 50 million naturalized Americans
in this country.
I'm aware of that, yes.
You didn't seem aware of it because you said
Americans versus immigrants.
But are you understanding that the process of getting
all these immigrants that come in here for,
also, the millions of immigrants.
It's up to the millions.
It's the last 20 years now.
And it has dramatically affected Americans
here in the country, which people like me
and everyone around here, we cannot find homes or even
get jobs within our own fields that we go to college for,
that we get into debt for.
And because more blue collar work,
especially in construction, agriculture, and so forth,
and the hospitality industry, we cannot get jobs
in those fields.
So it requires us.
Are you looking for a job in construction or agriculture?
I am not, no.
I went to college.
Many people here are in college or went to college,
but we can't even find jobs in our fields,
also because of the H-1B visa program as well.
But in regards of just your claim about immigrants
specifically, we cannot even get jobs to pay for housing.
Unemployment is at a record low right now,
even under Donald Trump.
And I'm not a Donald Trump fan, but I
would say unemployment under both Biden and Trump
has been at record low levels.
OK, is this in regards for American citizens?
Yes.
OK.
Well, I'm unaware of that statistic.
But from what I see, from what I can see here.
I'm an immigrant and an American.
And I employ many American citizens, both naturalized
and the ones born here.
I employ Americans.
No, my parents came as.
Americans as defined by you.
My parents came as immigrants and became naturalized.
So I'm not necessarily opposed to immigrants.
So you're the child of immigrants.
Correct.
I'm a child of immigrants.
I was born here.
But you don't accept that immigrants are Americans.
Not at this moment.
So your parents are not Americans?
No.
So hold on.
Your parents are not Americans.
They're citizens.
They became naturalized.
You just said you can't be citizens by being naturalized.
No, I was born here.
And I'm not opposed to naturalization.
But are your parents.
Except that I'm against naturalization.
Are you against naturalization?
No, I never said I was against naturalization.
You did.
You began.
Everyone who's here, they can play it back on YouTube.
You said Americans or immigrants.
Are your parents Americans or immigrants?
No, my parents are United States citizens.
But they're immigrants, you said.
No, they came here as immigrants.
However, but I want to make the claim that we can't even.
I came here as an immigrant.
I'm an immigrant.
But at this point, when they came, the United States economy.
I think people aren't happy with the way this is going for you.
The United States economy was not at.
It's better now.
The American economy is better than it's been for many years.
Not from the statistics I see.
And I can say that as someone who doesn't like Donald Trump.
I'm giving millions and billions of dollars
to people of minorities as well as immigrants.
The reason the economy is doing badly now
is because of Donald Trump's tariff policy.
We can't even get businesses.
Nothing to do with migrants.
In fact, the congressional.
They can't even start businesses.
I'm an immigrant.
I started a business.
No, I understand.
Because the SBA is giving people billions of loans.
Immigrants, I didn't take any loans from SBA.
I didn't take any loans from SBA.
I'm not saying you did.
But I'm saying that statistically speaking,
they're giving billions of loans to these people.
So should we do statistics?
According to statistics, immigrants
are 80% more likely to be entrepreneurs
than native-born Americans.
Sure, absolutely.
Immigrants are more likely to start businesses
and hire Americans.
No, I'm aware of that.
Immigrants are more likely to pay in taxes
than take out in benefits.
They're more likely to add to innovation and jobs and wages.
This is what the statistics show.
The Congressional Budget Office.
Let me just finish before I let you come back in.
The Congressional Budget Office, which
is bipartisan, Republicans and Democrats both use it.
They have said that the immigration surge that you
mentioned will lead to an extra $9 trillion
of GDP over the next 10 years.
That amounts to $65,000 per American household.
That's $65,000 for each and every one of you
holding up a red flag.
OK, I understand that, but-
All right, pause.
You've been voted out by the majority.
Please return to your seat.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.